Mss.Ms.Coll.137
American Philosophical Society
- V. Memoranda, 1969-1990; 2.0 Linear feet (Box 30-33)
  - National Science Foundation Memoranda, 1969-1990; 108.0 folders (Box 30-33)
    - Memorandum NS-691. Continuation of Fragments of Chapter Ten: Which Denominator?, 1988; Blackwell, T. E., (Thomas E.); Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
      Follows Memo 655. Revises Memo 680 and adds material to it.
    - Memorandum NS-692. How Science Writers and Others Quantify Expressions of Probability: A Proposed Codification, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-693. Some Reasons for Analyzing Tables Like Those We Apply ANOVA To, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-694. Preliminary Examination of Data in an ANOVA Table: Editing and Appreciating the Data, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-695. Method of Moments Estimation of Variance Components with Two-Way Analysis of Variance, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
      Corrected Memo 690 Plus an Alternative Model for Interaction in the Two-Way Analysis of Variance. Fragments for Chapter Ten
    - Memorandum NS-696. AIDS Testing: An Example with Two Nested Factors, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor; Schmid, Christopher H (Box 32)
      Part of Chapter Four
    - Memorandum NS-697. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-2, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-698. Revision of the One-Way Example for Chapter Four, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-699. Chapter Four, Revised, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-700. Illustration of the Sweeping Upward Procedure Using the Rat Feeding Data in Chapter Four, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-701. Three-Way Example: Tumor Size, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-702. Analysis of Variance, Chapter Ten. Which Denominator?, 1988; Blackwell, T. E., (Thomas E.); Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
      This chapter pools Memos 655, 678, 691, 695, 701.
    - Memorandum NS-703. Notes on Paull's Paper on Preliminary Tests of Significance in Analysis of Variance, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-704. Start of Chapter Four: 4.1 Decomposing Data into Overlays. 4.2 Overlays for One-Way Data, 1988; Schmid, Christopher H (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-705. Nail Polish and Pulse Oximetry: A Possible Example for Chapter I1, 1988; Hoaglin, David C. (David Caster), 1944- (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-706. ANOVA. Chapter 10. The Two-Way Unbalanced Design, 1988; Brown, Constance (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-707. Illustration of the Sweeping Upward Procedure Using the Rat Feeding Data in Chapter Four, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor (Box 32)
      Revision of Memo 700
    - Memorandum NS-708. Why F=2? The Mean-Square-per-Degree-of-Freedom Argument, 1988; Hoaglin, David C. (David Caster), 1944- (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-709. More of Chapter Four. 4C. What the Residuals Tell Us. 4D. Comparing Sizes of Overlays: The ANOVA Table, 1988; Schmid, Christopher H (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-710. More of Chapter Four. 4E. Designs with Two Crossed Factors. 4F. Interaction and Replication. 4G. Two Factor Designs with Replication, 1988; Schmid, Christopher H (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-712. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-2. Purposes of Analyzing Data that comes in a Form Inviting us to Apply Tools from the Analysis of Variance, 1988; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 32)
      Revision of Memo 697
    - Memorandum NS-713. Percentage of Americans who have Never Married: A Possible Example for Chapter I1, 1988; Hoaglin, David C. (David Caster), 1944- (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-714. Value Splitting Involving More Factors. Section D: The Dental Gold Example, 1988; Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-715. Methods for Studying Coincidences, 1988; Diaconis, Persi; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-716. ANOVA. Chapter 8. Components of Variance, 1989; Brown, Constance; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
    - Memorandum NS-717. ANOVA. Chapter 4. Introduction to Transformation, 1989; Emerson, John D.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 32)
      Replaces Memo 669
    - Memorandum NS-722. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-2. Purposes of Analyzing Data that come in a Form Inviting us to Apply Tools from the Analysis of Variance, 1989; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 33)
      Revision of Memorandum NS-712
    - Memorandum NS-746. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-1. Concepts and Examples in Analysis of Variance, 1990; Tukey, John W., Frederick Mosteller, and David C. Hoaglin (Box 33)
    - Memorandum NS-751. ANOVA. Chapter 005. Assessing Changes, 1990; Tukey, John W., Frederick Mosteller, and Cleo Youtz (Box 33)
      Revision of Memorandum NS-738.
    - Memorandum NS-756. ANOVA. Chapter 3. Types of Factors and their Structural Layouts, 1990; Singer, Judith D (Box 33)
    - Memorandum NS-758. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-2. Purposes of Analyzing Data that come in a Form Inviting us to Apply Tools from the Analysis of Variance, 1990; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 33)
      Revision of Memorandum NS-722.
    - Memorandum NS-760. ANOVA. Chapter Intro-3. Preliminary Examination of Data, 1990; Mosteller, Frederick, and David C. Hoaglin (Box 33)
    - Memorandum NS-762. ANOVA. Chapter 8. Components of Variance, 1990; Brown, Constance, and Frederick Mosteller (Box 33)
      Replaces Memorandum NS-750.
    - Memorandum NS-792. An Estimator of Tails of Probability Distributions. Example 1. Places in the US having 1980 populations greater than 100,000, 1990; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 33)
    - Memorandum NS-794. Tails of Probability Distributions. Example 2. Previously unmarried females who were married in the period 1925-1930 in Copenhagen, 1990; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 33)
    - Memorandum NS-795. Tails of Probability Distributions. Example 3. Notable tall buildings in North American cities, 1990; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 33)
  - New England Journal of Medicine Memoranda, 1983; 6.0 folders (Box 33)
    - NEJM Memorandum 161. Support Data for Project on Surgical Trials Reporting, 1983; Emerson, John D.; Hosseini, Hossein (Box 33)
    - NEJM Memorandum 168. Reporting Clinical Trials in General Surgical Journals, 1983; Emerson, John D.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 33)
      Revision of NEJM Memorandum 164
    - NEJM Memorandum 169. Estimating the Variance of the Group Means in One-Way ANOVA Designs, 1983; Emerson, John D. (Box 33)
    - NEJM Memorandum 171. P-values: Uses and Misuses, 1983; Ware, James H., Frederick Mosteller, and Joseph A. Ingelfinger (Box 33)
      Revision of NEJM Memorandum 167
    - NEJM Memorandum 173. Comparing Several Group Means, 1983; Godfrey, Katherine (Box 33)
      Revision of NEJM Memorandum 160
    - NEJM Memorandum 183. Reporting Clinical Trials in General Surgical Journals, 1983; Emerson, John D.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 33)
      Revision of NEJM Memorandum 168
- VI. Diplomas, Certificates, and Awards, 1938-2001; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 33-40)
  - Academic Regalia, n.d.; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 35)
    Academic hoods.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 36)
    Pewter bowl.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1978-1997 (Box 33)
    Includes material relating to Mosteller's election as president of the association and as a fifty-year member (Box 33); and the unveiling of a chemistry commemorative stamp design by the U.S. Postal Service (Box 35).
  - American Medical Writers' Association, 1996 (Box 37)
    Plaque in recognition of outstanding quality of the work, Medicine Worth Paying For: Assessing Medical Innovations (Harvard University Press, 1995)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1961 (Box 39)
    Certificate of membership.
  - American Psychological Association, 1997 (Box 37)
    Plaque for Distinguished Lifetime Contribution to Evaluation, Measurement, and Statistics.
  - American Statistical Association, 1986-2001 (Box 33-34, 36-37)
    Various awards (Box 33), including a plaque for Statistician of the Year from the Boston Chapter (Box 34), a certificate for being the association's president (Box 36), the 1992 Founders Award (Box 36), Statistician of the Year from the Sports Section (Box 37), and the Samuel S. Wilks Memorial Medal (Box 37).
  - Annual Reviews Inc., 1983 (Box 37)
    Certificate
  - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1938-1974 (Box 33-36)
    Includes commencement program (Box 33); diplomas--bachelor of science, master of science, honorary doctor of science (Box 34); academic hood (Box 35); and 50th-anniversary medal (Box 36).
  - Committee of Presidents of Statistical Societies, 1987 (Box 37)
    Plaque for R. A. Fisher Award.
  - Congressional Record, 1991 (Box 38)
    Oversized. Framed citation. Read before the Senate by Daniel Patrick Moynihan, June 27, 1991.
  - Drug Information Association, 1988 (Box 37)
    Plaque for Donald E. Francke Award
  - Evaluation Research Society, 1978 (Box 36)
    Gunnar and Alva Myrdal Prize. Plaque
  - Harvard University, 1971-1997 (Box 33, 36-38, 40)
    Diplomas and awards, including: inscribed photo album (empty) (Box 36); diploma in Latin (Box 37); Marvin Zelen Leadership Award in Statistical Science (Box 37); diploma for Doctor of Laws (Box 38); Professor Emeritus Award of Merit from the School of Public Health (Box 40); and, a certificate comemorating the creation of the Frederick Mosteller professorship in the School of Public Health (Box 40).
  - International Statistical Institute, 1977-1994 (Box 33)
  - Lazarsfeld Prize, 1980 (Box 33)
    From Clark C. Abt (ed.), Problems in American Social Policy Research
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1974 (Box 37)
    Includes a Rosette and Diploma of Membership.
  - National Advisory Council on Equality of Educational Opportunity, 1978 (Box 37)
    Plaque
  - National Cancer Institute, 1990 (Box 34)
    Certificate of Appreciation
  - New England Journal of Medicine (Box 36)
    Crystal container.
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1993 (Box 33)
  - Princeton University (Box 37)
    Diploma in Latin
  - Psychometric Society, 1958 (Box 36)
    Engraved wooden gavel.
  - Royal Statistical Society, 1977 (Box 36)
    Certificate for Honorary Fellowship in the society.
  - Sigma Xi Society, 1938 (Box 33)
  - United States. Department of Health and Human Services (Box 39)
    Certificate for service.
  - University of Chicago, 1973 (Box 33-34)
    Includes written introduction by David Wallace, convocation program, and honorary Doctor of Science diploma.
  - Wesleyan University, 1983 (Box 33-34)
    Commencement program and honorary Doctor of Science degree.
  - Yale University, 1981 (Box 33, 37)
    Includes introductory remarks and commencement program (Box 33), and diploma for honorary Doctor of Science degree (Box 37).